Hello.
Next, we're going to add some controls to our player blueprint.
If we open it up.
I actually think I made the camera a bit too close to my play character, so I'm just like the spring
go on and make up a value of 1000 just so it's a bit further back.
Next if we head over to the land graph.
So here inside of the graph, it's where we're going to write the code for how we should control and
move our player character.
The first thing we're going to do is create and reference this input mapping context, which has all
the controls for our game.
So in order to do that big begin play, this node will fire.
As soon as our game starts.
We're going to add the controls to our game.
If we just right click and we'll get controller.
And from here we just want to drag off the return value and cost to the player controller.
And this will allow us to reference the player controller that we're playing the game as.
And from the player controller, we're going to look for the enhanced input local player subsystem.
And this will basically allow us to add controls to our game.
And if we just drag up here and will add mapping context and for the mapping context, select the emcee
default that we made earlier.
And this basically add all the controls for our game.
But before we actually do this, we just want to drag off here and look for is valid and we want this
one with the question mark and just connect this into here.
And this is valid into here.
This is valid.
We'll basically just check to make sure that we can actually reference this enhanced input local player
subsystem and we just want to connect those to event back in play.
So as soon as the game starts, it will add these controls to our game.
Now that we've done this, we can code how the controls in our game will work in some free space.
If you just right click and look for jump, you should see this enhanced action events jump.
So just like this, I-A jump.
This is the action mapping jump that we made earlier.
And when we press the spacebar button, it's going to fire this trigger node.
And when this happens, we're going to make our player character jump.
So if you just drag off this trigger node and look for jump, this will make our player character automatically
jump.
When our player character stops pressing this baseball button.
We want our player character to stop jumping.
So off of the completed, if you just drag up here and force stop jumping.
And this will make it so our player character will no longer jump to test that.
Everything is working so far.
If you just go compile, save then close this and then click play in your project.
If you press the space problem.
If you click somewhere on the screen and then press the space button on the play, a character should
jump.
The next thing we're going to do is code it so our player character can move.
If we go back to our player blueprint in some free space, I'm going to right click and look for the
move.
And we want to select this one, The Enhanced Action event I move.
Now with our Enhanced Input Action Move event.
If you remember earlier when we created the key, I told you to just let this access one float because
we did this in our enhanced action move, We can see that it has this action value.
We're going to use this value to tell a game if the player character should move towards the left or
the right when the player presses the move button.
So I've triggered the first thing I need you to do is to drag off and add movement input.
Then here under the one direction in the x put a value of one.
This basically determines where in the world the player is going to move when we press this button.
The reason we're putting a value of one in the X value is because if I go to the viewport and select
my sprite.
I'm just going to change this to select and translate objects and if I just move this red arrow.
In the location, you're going to see that the value in the x axis is changing.
In 2D games, the player character normally only moves in one axis and that axis is going to be the
x axis in this project.
Because you can see when I move the player character in the x axis, they move towards the left or the
right.
So that's why we're putting a value of one in the X, Just make sure it's there.
Then for the action value, if you just connect this into here and actually if you just drag off the
trigger and print string.
And connect this action value into here.
I'm just going to close this and go back to my emcee underscore default.
If you remember whether, A, we made it negate this value.
This will basically mean that when the player presents the upon this value is going to be negative.
However, for the DBA, we left this blank.
So that means by default it's going to be positive.
So if I just close this and I'll go play.
Click somewhere on the screen and I press the A button.
We're going to see its print shrinking negative one.
And my player character is moving negatively in the x axis.
However, if I press the D one, then it's going to print string one and my player character positively
moves in the x axis.
Nice.
There are a couple more things I want to show you with the controls.
So if I go back to my player blueprint.
If you want to change how high the player character can jump, you can go over to character movement
and here under details if you look for jump.
The velocity currently is set to 420.
If I change this to something like 500, that's going to mean the player character will jump a lot higher.
So you can just do that if you want to kind of like change how high the player character jumps.
There are also some more things we can do with the jump if I set the player BP.
And I look for jump out.
Currently the jump max count is one.
If I change this to be something like three.
Close this and go play the player count.
It's going to be up to jump three times.
There's one more jumping thing I want to show you, and that is the jump time.
If I just look for a jump with the player selected and go jump back the whole time.
If I change this value to be something like one, I'm going to be able to hold my spacebar button for
one second and my player character will continuously jump.
I'll kind of visually show you what I mean if I could play.
And I just tapped the space up on my play.
Carter will just jump a bit.
However, if I hold the space for one second, my play, Carter is going to continuously jump.
So that's what that jump Max hold kind of does.
If you don't want that setting affecting your player characters, jump here under the jump, Max whole
time.
Just change this back to be a value of zero and it won't affect that.